Israel says Fatma attempted murder, and yet she was only detained, not charged.
She didn't go to trial. She wasn't given any opportunity to defend herself.
And this is a story we keep hearing again and again from released prisoners,
that they aren't given due process, and yet this crime exists alongside their names.
The Israeli Prison Service responded to these allegations, saying
National security prisoners who were released from the Israeli prison during the past two days
were serving time for serious crimes, such as attempted murder, assault, and throwing explosives.
All prisoners in IPS custody are held according to the law.
That's not true. CNN broke down the numbers in a list of 300 Palestinian prisoners
identified by Israel as eligible for release.
80% are listed as just detained, which means they have not been formally sentenced.
Israel operates two systems of law in the occupied territories.
Palestinians under the military, Israelis under civil law,
creating a low bar for the arrest of increasing numbers of Palestinians.
And as Israeli hardliners like Ben Gavir and others in this far-right government
seek to characterize every Palestinian as a terrorist.
That number is rising every day.